

# ABIGAIL CASSO UX Designer

706-207-5401 • abbycasso@gmail.com • abbycasso.myprofile.com

#### SKILLS

Wireframing

Prototyping

**Usability Testing** 

User Research

IΑ

User Flows

Personas

UI Design

Responsive Design

HTML

**CSS** 

Java

**Technical Writing** 

Project Management

## TOOLS

Adobe XD

Lucid Chart

Usability Hub

Optimal Sort

Marvel

Trello

Microsoft Suite

Google Docs

Figma

Atom

#### PROFILE

UX Designer driven by the fulfillment gained from providing people with useful solutions to realworld problems. Having an educational background in science and professional experience in the medical field helped shape me into an analytical yet empathetic individual, providing me with the necessary skills to identify users' needs and deliver valuable and enjoyable end experiences.

#### EDUCATION

CareerFoundry | 2022

UX Design Program

• A UX Design Program that utilizes project-based learning to allows students to apply UX design principles in order to generate design deliverables & build a portfolio. In this program I learned & utilized the design thinking process to create a mobile app & a responsive web app. In addition to gaining proficiencies in UX design skills, I learned HTML, CSS, & Java basics in the Frontend Development for Designers Specialization Course to build a portfolio site from scratch.

The University of Georgia | 2015

Bachelor of Science in Biology, Franklin College of Arts & Science

#### EXPERIENCE

#### Austin Skin

Community Liaison & Social Media Manager / Medical Assistant | 2020-2021

- Developed & presented protocols on cosmetic services to educate staff members
- Worked closely with skincare & device company reps to market/promote practice
- Generated & posted content for the practice's social media accounts & website
- · Assisted physicians with Mohs Micrographic Surgery and other clinical duties

# Westlake Dermatology

Medical Assistant | 2018-2020

- Generated and presented cosmetic quotes for procedures with patients
- Educate patients on diagnoses, treatment, and care relating to their examinations
- Assist physicians during exams and treatments

## Vitalogy Skincare

Medical Assistant | 2017-2018

- Communicated pathology results and educated patients on diagnoses & treatment
- Assisted physicians with surgical, medical, and diagnostic procedures

## Worldwide Express

Account Executive | 2016-2017

- Developed new business by prospecting and identifying leads
- Collaborated with other teams to understand customer's needs & grow business
- Presented and negotiated with customers regarding fees, products, and services
- · Inducted into the WWElite Club, an internal sales achievement award recognizing individuals who eclipsed \$7,500 in average weekly revenue at their six month mark